[Flowers for sale!]
卖花 卖花
Sir, sir!
先生 先生 先生
Would you like to buy some flowers?
您要不要买花啊
What's happening inside?
师傅 里面怎么了
Not sure.
不知道
They're making arrests.
抓人呢
Have they caught anyone?
抓到了还是跑了呀
Not a clue.
不清楚
Can I leave it here with you for now?
我这能先放您这儿吗
I'll come back for it shortly.
我一会儿过来拿
Sure, no problem.
好的 没问题
Thanks.
谢谢啊
I'm telling you,
我跟你说
these days
这个年头
they just arrest people left and right.
动不动就抓人
What's going on up there?
上面干吗呢
Captain Chen, how was your day?
陈队长下班了
Hi, Captain Chen.
陈队长
Captain Chen, you're back.
陈队长回来了
I slid your letter under your door.
信我给你塞屋里了啊
What did you say?
你说什么
I put your letter inside your room.
信我给你塞到屋里了
Young man, slow down when you run.
年轻人慢点儿跑
[Don't trip and fall.]
别摔着
[Take care as autumn turns chilly,]
入秋顿凉
[stick to your path]
若家中生变
[and do not worry about us.]
勿念
[May all your bridges be sturdy]
愿你桥都坚固
[and all your tunnels bright.]
隧道都光明
[Captain.]
组长
they're from the household registration.
这是我登记户口的收获
These are all invalidated,
这些都是作废的
yet to be canceled
还没有到公安局
at the Public Security Bureau.
注销的户籍卡
These are empty households.
这几个是空户
The owners have moved out of the area.
户主已经迁居外地了
I'd like to borrow
这张户籍卡
this card for a week.
我想借用一个星期
Then I will destroy it.
之后我会把它销毁
No matter what happens,
不管发生任何情况
no one will use
都不会再有人
this card again.
使用这张户籍卡
After a week,
一星期以后
you just need to go through the normal procedure
你只需要到户籍科
at the registration office to cancel it,
按正常程序去注销
nothing else.
其余的什么都不用做
Understood.
我知道了
Are you trying to ask me
你小子是不是想问我
when I'll end your dormant state?
什么时候结束休眠状态
When?
什么时候
We need to wait a bit longer.
还要再等等
The central committee has sent
中央已经派同志
someone to Shanghai
到上海来做
for organization rebuilding.
组织重建工作
But our force was
但是毕竟
greatly weakened in the KMT controlled area.
白区破坏得太严重了
Now, the most important thing
眼下最重要的
is to preserve our strength.
是保存实力
If it weren't for this
如果不是这次情况
particular situation,
过于特殊
I shouldn't have asked you
我其实都不应该
to help me with the documentation.
拜托你来帮我提供证件
I understand.
我明白
I'll wait patiently.
我也会耐心等待的
Can't find anywhere
一个落脚的地方
to stay?
都找不到吗
I don't know who to turn to.
我不知道应该找谁
Don't you have any relatives in Shanghai?
你在上海没有亲戚吗
What about your parents' friends?
你父母的朋友呢
I don't know them.
我都不认识
In fact, I had a French teacher.
不过我有一个法语老师
However,
可是
she left Shanghai
她前几天
a few days ago
就已经离开上海了
and I don't know
也不知道
when she will return.
她什么时候能回来
I can't go back
我现在也不能
to my own home now,
回自己家了
can I?
是不是
The bedroom is yours. I'll take the couch.
你睡卧室 我睡沙发
Sir,
哥哥
did you come to Shanghai
你是从其他地方
from somewhere else?
来上海的吗
I've already bought a train ticket
三天后回南京的火车票
back to Nanjing in three days.
我已经买好了
Until then,
在此之前
you can stay here.
你都可以住在这儿
I'll also
我也会替你
cover your meals.
付一日三餐的饭钱
Other than that,
除此之外
I'm not responsible for anything.
我不负责你的其他事情
Deal?
同意吗
Deal.
同意
What grade are you in?
你读几年级
Second grade. I'm 8 years old.
小学二年级 我八岁了
If anyone asks,
如果有人问起
we'll say
对外就说
we're cousins.
我们是兄妹关系
Okay.
好
Any more questions?
还有什么问题吗
What's your name?
那你叫什么名字
I'm Hua Zhen.
我叫华桢
What's the matter?
你有事儿
Brother Hua Zhen,
华桢哥哥
how much do you
你一个月的薪水
earn a month?
有多少钱啊
What?
什么
Is it a lot?
有很多吗
40 silver dollars every month.
我一个月四十块补贴
I'm not sure if that's a lot.
不知道多少算多
[Hua Zhen,]
华桢
[I need a favor.]
我有事相托
[Does it matter a lot to you?]
这件事对你很重要吗
Extremely.
至关重要
[It must remain a secret]
千万不能让任何人
[from anyone else.]
知道这件事
Liang, this is Zhen speaking.
哥 是我
I need your help
拜托你帮我
with something.
打听一件事儿
I'm stepping out.
我出去一趟
You should keep a low profile.
你应该少出门走动
But I have
但我有个
an important call to make.
很重要的电话要打
I know you're looking
我知道你想找一个
for a place to stay,
落脚的地方
but it's best to keep out of sight
但在凶手被抓到之前
until the culprit is caught.
你最好少露面
How about you come with me?
要不你跟着我
I've said before,
我说过
I only provide you with food and shelter,
我只负责你的吃的住的
not
其他的事情
anything else.
我都不负责
Excuse me,
姐姐
may I use the phone,
我想用一下电话
please?
好吗
Why
小妹妹
are you alone?
你怎么是一个人啊
Where are your parents?
你父母呢
Why aren't they with you?
他们怎么没有陪着你啊
They're in the room.
他们就在房间呢
If
小妹妹
something happens to
你一个小孩子
a child like you
在我们饭店
in our hotel,
万一出了什么事儿
we would be blamed.
我们是要担责的
Could you
你看这样好不好
write down your room number here?
你把房间号写下来
In case of anything special,
万一有事儿啊
I can contact your parents,
我也好通知你的父母
okay?
好吗
Just write it here.
写在这儿就行了
Thanks, but...
不用了姐姐
my parents are upstairs,
我父母都在楼上
I just need the phone
我借个电话就走
and I won't wander off.
我不会乱跑的
Alright then.
那好吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Duoci, this is all I have.
多慈 我只有这么多了
It's yours now.
都给你吧
Thank you, Yimo.
谢谢你 依默
It's just...
我就是
could I possibly borrow
我现在能找你
some money from you?
借一点点钱吗
Not much.
就一点点
Here, Duoci.
多慈 给你
I'll pay you back for this.
这些钱我会还给你的
Where are your mom and dad?
你爸爸妈妈呢
Um...
那个 那个
is Luoyan home?
罗妍在家吗
Bye.
再见
Is this Yubai speaking?
是钰白吗
Oh, okay, thank you.
好 谢谢钰白
I only have 6.2 Silver dollars,
多慈 我只有六块二
here you are.
都给你了
Thank you.
谢谢你 玉常
You're welcome.
不用客气
Take care.
再见
Staying in your room all day?
你一整天都没出门啊
There's nowhere to go.
没什么地方可去
Hello?
喂
Brother,
哥
how's the investigation
我拜托你打听的事儿
I asked you about?
怎么样了
I was about to tell you about that
你不问我啊
even if you didn't call.
我还要告诉你呢
[Deng Mingyuan is in big trouble.]
邓铭远惹上大麻烦了
[From now on,]
你从现在开始
[you must distance yourself from him,]
跟他划清界限
[or you'll end up in trouble too.]
否则你也会惹上麻烦
What kind of trouble?
什么麻烦
He's been found out as a communist.
他被查出是共产党
[The day he came to Dad's birthday party,]
他来爸爸生日宴那天
he was taken away right after leaving.
出门就被带走
The Party Affairs Investigation Bureau
党务调查处的人
has already visited Dad.
已经来过家里找爸爸
Everyone in our family
家里的所有人
will be investigated.
都要接受调查
Who took him away?
谁把他带走了
[Does that matter?]
这很重要吗
I know you used to
我知道你以前
say Deng Mingyuan
老把邓铭远
was your mentor,
说成是你的恩师
[but you should stop]
但是以后这种话
[saying that now, Okay?]
不要再说了 好吗
He couldn't possibly be a communist.
他不可能是共产党
He accompanied the former premier to the north,
他曾陪伴先总理北上
and followed the Chairman on the Northern Expedition.
又跟着委员长东征北伐
He has convictions and qualifications.
他有信仰有资历
How could he
他怎么可能
join the Communist Party?
参加共产党呢
Exactly, that's why it's foolish.
是啊 所以说他糊涂啊
He threw away a promising future
放着大好的前程不要
to join
非要去投奔
the Communist Party.
共产党
Brother,
哥
if he is a communist,
如果他是共产党
what will they do to him?
那些人会拿他怎么样
[If he really is a communist,]
如果他真是共产党
[he and everyone close to him]
他跟他身边的人
[could be executed.]
都得掉脑袋
By the way, I must ask you,
对了 我还要问问你呢
did you go to Shanghai
你到底是自己
at your will
跑去上海玩的
or did Deng Mingyuan
还是邓铭远
send you there for something?
委托你干什么啊
[Why did you rush off to Shanghai]
怎么那天你们一见面
[right after meeting him?]
你就跑去上海了
I was just bored at home
就是在家待得无聊
and wanted to go out.
想出来逛逛
Oh,
对了
I met a kid
我在上海
in Shanghai.
遇到了一个小孩儿
Her family has undergone some changes.
她家里出现了一些变故
[If I bring her back to Nanjing]
如果我把她带回南京
[when I report to the fleet,]
我去舰队报到的时候
[could you guys help look after her?]
你们方便照顾一下她吗
What kid could you possibly know?
你能认识什么小孩儿
Did Deng Mingyuan
是不是邓铭远
ask you to find her?
让你去找的
[Hua Zhen,]
华桢
[I'm officially warning you now,]
我现在正式警告你
Deng Mingyuan has accomplices in Shanghai too.
邓铭远在上海也有同党
You must distance yourself not just from him,
你不光要跟他划清界限
but also from his associates
他身边的人和事
and their affairs!
你都不能沾染
[If you dare bring back someone]
如果你敢把邓铭远的人
[related to Deng Mingyuan,]
带回来
[our whole family could be involved!]
咱们全家都得受牵连
It's just a kid
就是随便遇到的
I happened to meet.
一个小孩儿
I was just asking.
我随口问问
Brother,
哥
if he is a communist,
如果老师是共产党
he must know he couldn't escape
他在踏进华家的那一刻
when he stepped into the Hua's house.
就知道脱不了身
Why would he still come?
你说他为什么还要进来
Who knows what these communists are thinking?
共产党不是你能搞懂的
Aren't you due to report back
你不是还有一个月
to the fleet in a month?
就要回舰队报到了吗
You want to watch movies, visit fairs,
你想看电影 逛庙会
eat eight-treasure duck, sweet and sour fish,
吃八宝鸭 糖醋鱼
go ahead.
随你
[Immediately return to Nanjing once you've had enough fun,]
玩够了马上回南京
[and stop snooping around at night,]
不要半夜里瞎打听
[got it?]
听见了吗
Understood.
知道了
[Deng Mingyuan is in big trouble.]
邓铭远惹上大麻烦了
[He's been found out as a communist.]
他被查出是共产党
[From now on,]
你从现在开始
[you must distance yourself from him,]
跟他划清界限
[or you'll end up in trouble too.]
否则你也会惹上麻烦
Through a thousand books, one walks with the ancients.
读破千卷 神交古人
[You must distance yourself not just from him,]
你不光要跟他划清界限
[but also from his associates]
他身边的人和事
[and their affairs!]
你都不能沾染
[If you dare bring back someone]
如果你敢把邓铭远的人
[related to Deng Mingyuan,]
带回来
[our whole family could be involved!]
咱们全家都得受牵连
[Sir, here's your receipt.]
先生 收据您拿好
Thank you.
谢谢
I've handled the paperwork
手续我已经办好了
and reserved enough for the room.
也预留了足够多的房钱
You can
如果你愿意
stay here
你可以一直住在这儿
as long as you like.
多久都行
You can eat
一日三餐
all your meals at the hotel restaurant.
都可以去饭店的餐厅吃
The chefs here are quite good.
这儿厨师手艺还不错
I just read in the newspaper
刚刚我看了报纸
that
上面说
the representatives from the city's labor and commerce unions
市工会和商会的代表
have petitioned the Public Security Bureau
已经向公安局请愿
to pursue the murderer vigorously
要求全力缉捕凶手
and maintain order in Shanghai.
维护上海治安
So, you don't have to worry about
所以你不用担心
this case being ignored.
这个案子没有人管
The demon
那个坏人
was wearing
他自己穿的
a police uniform, though.
就是警察的衣服
Will the police really handle it?
警察真的会管吗
At least that's what the paper says.
至少报纸上是这么写的
After my parents and I
我和爸爸妈妈
moved into the Wenhua Hotel,
搬进文华饭店以后
they never opened the door for anyone.
他们从不给任何人开门
They definitely wouldn't have opened it
要不是因为那天
if the killer hadn't been dressed
凶手穿的是警察的衣服
as a police officer.
他们绝对不会开门的
Apart from
你的父母
the prominent business figures
除了报纸上写的
as stated in the paper,
沪上名商之外
do your parents have
是不是还有别的
any other identities?
什么身份
Any other identities?
别的什么身份
My parents
我爸爸妈妈
own a large
他们开了一间
herbal medicine factory.
很大的药材厂
Other than that...
别的
I don't know.
别的我就不知道了
Never mind.
算了
The paper also mentioned
这报纸上还说啊
that it's likely you were also killed.
你有可能也遇害了
It's great, in some way.
消息有误也好
At least
起码
the killer won't know
凶手不会知道
your whereabouts.
你的下落了
After I leave,
等我走了
you can go to the restaurant downstairs
你就可以去下面的餐厅
for lunch.
吃午饭
Just take the keys and go.
直接拿着钥匙去就行
You won't need to pay.
不用付现金
The keys are on the table.
钥匙就在桌子上
Brother Hua Zhen,
华桢哥哥
if I give you some money,
如果我给你一些钱
could you stay in Shanghai
你能在上海
a little longer?
多留一段时间吗
Hello?
喂
Okay, I understand.
好 我知道了
I'll come down right now.
马上下来
My ride is here.
接我的车已经到了
I...
我
This envelope
这个信封里面
has 23 silver dollars in it,
有二十三块钱
borrowed from my classmates.
是我找同学借的
They're just kids too,
他们也是小孩子
so they don't have much pocket money.
零花钱不多
I've asked
我已经找了
all the classmates I could,
所有我能找的同学
and only
一共
borrowed 23 silver dollars.
只凑到了二十三块钱
This ruby necklace
这条红宝石项链
was a birthday gift
是我六岁的时候
I picked out myself when I went to a temple fair
第一次和爸爸妈妈
with my parents
一起逛庙会
for the first time when I was six.
我自己挑选的生日礼物
Can l hire you
我用这些
to find
全部雇你
the killer
替我找凶手
with them?
行吗
Weren't you out making
你昨天出去打电话
a phone call yesterday
不是在给自己
to find a place to stay?
找落脚的地方
I already have a bed to sleep in.
我也已经有床睡觉了呀
Brother Hua Zhen,
华桢哥哥
you said
你说过
you earn 40 silver dollars per month.
你每个月能挣四十块钱
I don't know
我不知道
how much this ruby necklace
这条红宝石项链
can fetch,
能换多少钱
but it's the best thing
但这是我现在有的
I have right now.
最好的东西
Can I hire you for a month
我用这些雇你一个月
with them?
行吗
I'm sorry.
对不起
This is...
这是
glass,
玻璃
not a gem.
不是宝石
Brother Hua Zhen!
华桢哥哥
This book, I don't understand it.
这本书 我看不懂
I'd like to give it to you.
我想把它送给你
Brother Hua Zhen,
华桢哥哥
thank you for saving me.
谢谢你救了我
Hua Zhen!
华桢
Long time no see, An Yin.
好久不见 安殷
Watch your tone.
注意态度啊
I'm now the director
我现在可是
of the Assistant's Office
淞沪警备司令部
at the Shanghai Garrison Command,
副官处处长
Director An.
安处长
Just kidding.
闹着玩呢
Get in and we'll talk.
走 上车说
You called me yesterday
你昨天给我打电话
about that case.
说那案子
I checked,
我打听了
and it indeed was filed by the Fourth Station House
确实是十六铺分局
of the Shiliupu Police Station.
第四警察所立的案
Did you know
你跟被杀的那对夫妻
the murdered couple?
认识啊
No,
不认识
just someone
就是有人
asked me to inquire.
托我帮忙打听
This case is a bit unusual.
这案子是有点儿不一样
That couple were well-known
那对夫妻在上海
in Shanghai.
很有名望
Usually,
按理说
a case this big
这种大案应该
should go directly to the Public Security Bureau,
直接上调公安局
not just a police station.
不会在一个警察所立案
I went to the bureau to ask about it,
我去他们总局打听情况
and they were evasive.
对方也是跟我避重就轻
I personally went,
按理说我都亲自去了
and if it were
如果只是个
just a normal criminal case,
普通的刑事案
they wouldn't be secretive,
多少看在我们家面子上
at least out of respect for our family.
也不至于跟我保密呀
So,
所以说
it might be something fishy.
可能是有问题的
You just mentioned
你刚才说
that the Shanghai couple
那对上海的夫妻
were well-known.
很有名望
Do you know anything
你清楚他们的
about them specifically?
具体情况吗
I'll spare you
明面上那些头衔
their official titles.
就不说了
This couple had no party affiliations
这对夫妻没有党派
but were well-connected with government officials.
但跟政府官员来往很多
It might be because
可能是因为
of their business,
生意的原因吧
they were especially close with people
跟海军部的人
from the Navy Shipyard.
关系尤为密切
Why are you
我说你小子
so interested
怎么对这个案子
in this case?
这么感兴趣
How about
要不然干脆
let me give you a tip?
我给你出一招啊
The Public Security Bureau is recruiting new police officers.
公安局正在招新警员
Just arrange someone
你直接安排个人
to apply for the position.
去应招当警察
What's that saying,
那句话怎么说来着
all's fair in war?
兵不厌诈
If they won't tell us,
撬不开敌人的嘴
we'll infiltrate them.
咱们就打入敌人内部
Isn't that what you learned in
这不是谍报侦查课
espionage and reconnaissance?
学的吗
I'm joking.
我跟你开玩笑
Why so serious?
那么严肃干吗
I know.
我知道
Look at you.
你小子
Officer,
警官
you mentioned the name Meng Duoci,
您说的孟多慈
but there's no record of that name.
这个名字查不到
However, a girl
但是前两天
who looked a lot like her
确实有个跟她
did make a phone call here
长得很像的女孩儿
a few days ago.
在这里打过电话
I saw she was alone
我当时啊 看她一个人
and took a bit more care with her.
还多关心了两句
I asked her
我当时让她
to write down her room number.
把房间号写下来
She wrote a five,
她写了一个五
but then she erased it.
但是又抹掉了
Alright, you can drop me off here.
行了 就送到这儿了
Give your friend a word of advice:
劝你朋友一句
don't get too curious.
别太好奇了
I'm afraid that the complexity of this case
这个案子的复杂
lies not in the case itself,
恐怕不在案件本身
but in what's hidden behind it.
而是背后另有隐情
Got it,
知道了
thanks.
谢了
Safe travels.
一路顺风
The train to Nanjing
前往南京的火车
is about to depart.
马上发车了
Dear passengers, please hurry up.
请各位旅客抓点紧
The train to Nanjing
前往南京的火车
is about to depart.
马上发车了
Please hurry up, passengers.
请各位旅客抓点紧
[Dear passengers,]
各位旅客
[The train will soon depart.]
马上就要发车了
[Please stow your luggage, and mind your safety.]
把行李放好 注意安全
[Your attention please,]
各位乘客请注意
[please stow your luggage.]
行李放好
[The train is about to depart.]
马上发车了
[Dear passengers,]
各位乘客请注意
[please show your tickets]
提前出示一下证件
[as the ticket checks will soon begin.]
马上要检车票了
[Duoci.]
多慈
[Duoci, it's me.]
多慈 是我
Hello,
你好
I was staying in room 530.
我之前住在五三零房间
There was a girl with me.
有个跟我一起的女孩儿
Have you seen her leave the hotel?
你有看见她出饭店吗
She's about this tall,
就大概这么高
wears a pink dress every day,
每天穿一粉色的衣服
and has two braids.
梳了两个辫子
Was her family name Meng?
她是不是姓孟
How did you know?
你怎么知道
An officer was just here
刚刚有位警官来过了
asking about
也是打听
the same little girl you mentioned.
您说的这位小女孩儿
Was she taken away by him?
她被他带走了吗
Sorry,
我没太注意
I didn't pay much attention.
不好意思啊
Duoci!
多慈
Hello,
你好
have you seen
请问有没有见过
a girl of about this height?
一个这么高的女孩儿
No.
没看到
Duoci!
多慈
[I definitely]
我上午明明
[made the bed this morning.]
叠好了里面的被子
[How did it get so messy?]
现在怎么乱七八糟的
[You know what? The door]
对啊 我刚才来的时候
[was open when I came earlier.]
这门还是开着的
[Don't know who would do such a thing.]
也不晓得谁这么无聊
Meng Duoci.
孟多慈
it's me.
是我
That policeman came back again.
刚才那个警察又来了
Are you hurt?
有没有受伤
No,
没有
I was hiding under the blankets the whole time.
我一直躲在被窝里
I'm fine.
我没事
Okay, no more crying now.
行 不哭了
Don't cry.
不哭了啊
I wanted to follow him
我想追上去
to see what he looks like,
看看他长什么样子
but
可是
I was afraid he might notice me.
我又害怕会被他发现
You did very well already.
你已经做得很好了
I'm sorry,
对不起
I almost made a big mistake.
我差点酿成了一个大错
Where are we going?
我们去哪儿
To a different place to stay.
换个地方住
Will the killer
凶手是不是
come back?
还会再来
If he does,
如果他要是再来
I could ask the hotel staff for help.
我就去向饭店的人求助
They might help me.
他们说不定会帮我
But if I leave,
可我要是走了
won't the killer lose track of me?
凶手不就找不到我了吗
Whether or not
不管能不能
we can catch the killer,
帮你找到凶手
I can't use you as bait.
我都不可能拿你当诱饵
What's wrong?
怎么了
Are you staying to help me?
你要留下来帮我
You're not leaving?
你不走了
Well...
反正
I already missed the train.
已经错过火车了
Hello.
您好
Do you have any rooms available?
请问还有空的房间吗
Yes,
有的有的
we have a suite still available.
刚好还空着一套
But our rents
不过咱们这房租
are a bit high.
有些贵啊
Price is not a problem.
价格不是问题
Sir, you've come
先生 您找好公寓
to the right place.
还真是来对地方了
Of all the streets around,
方圆几条街
our apartments are the best.
就属我们这儿最好
Not only is it quiet here,
我们这儿呢不但安静
but our residents are
而且住客都是些
all reputable ladies and gentlemen.
有身份的太太先生
The rent for your room
您这间房间呢
is a bit high,
租金是贵了点
but it's the best.
但也是最好的
It has everything you need,
屋子里该有的都有
including a telephone.
连电话都给装上了
Please.
请进
Feel free to take a look.
您随便看
Do a lot of people
这间公寓
come and go from this apartment?
平常进出的人多吗
Are you worried about theft?
您是担心丢东西是吧
Rest assured,
请放心
everyone must register with me,
来人都要在我这儿登记
so no thieves can slip in.
混不进小偷
Okay,
好
I'll take the room.
这间房我要了
Please sign in here.
您先登记一下
Here are the keys.
钥匙您收好了
Let me know
有什么需要的
if you need anything.
尽管叫我
Sure,
好
thank you.
谢谢
The reason I came to Shanghai
我之所以来上海
was to deliver a book for someone.
是替一个人来送书
It wasn't until
直到我看见
I saw the ship tickets and identity papers inside the book
书里的船票和证件
that I realized
我才明白
I wasn't just delivering a book,
我送的不是书
[but a chance for your family]
而是你们一家人
[to survive.]
活着的机会
Is he a very important friend to you?
他是你很重要的朋友吗
More important than a friend.
比朋友更重要
To me,
对我而言
he's like
他就是像启明星
the morning star.
一样的人
Now that I've decided to stay,
现在我决定留下来
there are two things you need to know.
有两件事儿得告诉你
First,
第一
for some reasons,
因为一些原因
I can't take you back to Nanjing,
我不能带你回南京
nor can I send you to an orphanage
也不能把你交给福利院
or foster care,
或者寄养机构
as it might
因为这很有可能
bring them trouble.
给他们带来麻烦
So, for now,
所以这段时间
you'll have to stay with me.
你只能跟我待在一起
Okay.
好
Second,
第二
to others, we will
对外我们就
call each other cousins.
以表兄妹相称
No problem.
好
But I don't know how to take care of a child.
可我不会照顾小孩儿
I'm not really a child.
我也不算小孩儿呀
Alright... Okay.
行 行吧
Actually, I still
其实我心里
have some doubts.
还有一些疑惑
Maybe catching the killer
也许抓到凶手
will provide some answers.
就能找到答案了
But after a month,
但一个月之后
whether we catch the killer or not,
不管能不能抓到凶手
I must return to Nanjing.
我都必须回南京
Here's your new identification.
这是你的新证件
For now,
这段时间
your name is Li Qiushi.
你就叫黎秋实这个名字
And you?
那你呢
[Xiang Yuansheng.]
向远生
Brother Zhen,
华桢哥哥
where are you going
你要用这个身份
with this identity?
去哪儿啊